const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the effect of propylthiouracil on thyroid hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrophy of thyroid follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits oxidation of iodide and coupling of iodine","bool":true},{"option":"Hyper activates Na-I symporter","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit T3 release from thyroglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivates thyroglobulin","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Amine hormones are synthesized from which precursor?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which is the most likely cause of epigastric pain?","answers":[{"option":"Appendicitis","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD)","bool":true},{"option":"Gallstones","bool":false},{"option":"Diverticulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic rupture","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 7-year-old boy, who is healthy and school-going, comes to the outpatient department accompanied by his parents, for the evaluation of short stature. His bone age is 5 years, and height age is 5 years. There are no dysmorphic features. Routine laboratory investigations are normal. Which of the following is the most appropriate next investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Karyotype","bool":false},{"option":"DNA studies","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone levels","bool":true},{"option":"Somatostatin levels","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 7-year-old boy comes to the clinic for evaluation of short stature. He is shorter than his peers. His bone age is 4 years and his height is equivalent to that in a 5-year-old child(3rd percentile). No chronic diseases run in the family. Laboratory investigations reveal no abnormal findings. What is the most likely reason for his short stature?","answers":[{"option":"Familial short stature","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Constitutional growth delay","bool":true},{"option":"Dwarfism","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A patient comes with the fear that someone is trying to kill him. Which type of delusion is this termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Mixed delusion","bool":false},{"option":"Paranoid delusion","bool":true},{"option":"Erotomanic delusion","bool":false},{"option":"Grandiose delusion","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic delusion","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of these is the term used for the false perception of external stimuli which actually exist in reality?","answers":[{"option":"Miracle","bool":false},{"option":"Delusion","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mirage","bool":false},{"option":"Illusion","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of these is the false perception of something which is not a fact?","answers":[{"option":"Psychosis","bool":false},{"option":"Delusion","bool":true},{"option":"Hypnosis","bool":false},{"option":"Amnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Illusion","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of strychnine?","answers":[{"option":"Antagonism of glycine receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Stimulation of analgesic pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of selective serotonin uptake receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulation of inhibitory pathways (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Depression of excitatory pathways","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A child is brought to the emergency department with a history of ‘alleged’ snake bite. There is no swelling and no bite mark is seen on examination. He is anxious, has dyspnea, and is unable to open his eyes. The blood clotting mechanism observed for 20 minutes is normal. Which of the following is the best initial step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Do not give anti snake venom (ASV) and observe the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Give anti snake venom (ASV) and observe the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Give antihistamines","bool":false},{"option":"Give anxiolytic and reassure the patient","bool":true},{"option":"Give anti snake venom (ASV) and neostigmine","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"The poisoning caused by which of the following substances presents with gastrointestinal irritation, black-colored urine, and loin pain?","answers":[{"option":"Opium","bool":false},{"option":"Strychnine","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Naphthalene","bool":true},{"option":"Organophosphorus","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which snake venom causes rhabdomyolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Russell viper venom","bool":false},{"option":"Krait venom","bool":false},{"option":"Cobra venom","bool":false},{"option":"Sea snake venom","bool":true},{"option":"Black mamba venom","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 20-year-old woman comes to the emergency department with complaints of nausea, vomiting, abdominal cramps, diarrhea, fever, and chills after she consumed a raw beef dish at a restaurant that she had last night. She had the meal nearly sixteen hours ago and has been experiencing abdominal discomfort since. What organism is most likely to be responsible for her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Bacillus cereus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella enterica","bool":true},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 7-year-old boy picks a seed from the park and chewed and ingested it. He later develops extreme muscle contractions and convulsions. He gets diagnosed with strychnine poisoning. Which of the following defects occurs in strychnine poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"It releases neurotoxins","bool":false},{"option":"It affects the anterior horn of the spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"It is characterized by loin pain","bool":false},{"option":"It presents with dark-colored urine","bool":false},{"option":"It affects the posterior horn of the spinal cord","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of carbamate poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"Reversible inhibition of 5-alpha reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Depression of inhibitory pathways (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Reversible inhibition of acetylcholinesterase","bool":true},{"option":"Irreversible inhibition of acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulation of inhibitory pathways (GABA)","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of these is an ultra short-acting insulin?","answers":[{"option":"Protamine zinc insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin degludec","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin lispro","bool":true},{"option":"Insulin lente","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin detemir","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of these was the first sulfonylurea used to treat diabetes mellitus?","answers":[{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorpropamide","bool":true},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Glimepiride","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of these is incorrect about insulin?","answers":[{"option":"Insulin lispro is an ultra short-acting insulin","bool":false},{"option":"It is orally active","bool":true},{"option":"Insulin aspart is an ultra short-acting insulin","bool":false},{"option":"It is a naturally-secreted hormone","bool":false},{"option":"It can be synthesized synthetically","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which oral diabetic drug inhibits hepatic gluconeogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Metformin","bool":true},{"option":"Chlorpropamide","bool":false},{"option":"Gliclazide","bool":false},{"option":"Glimepiride","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin lispro","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of propylthiouracil (PTU)?","answers":[{"option":"Depression of inhibitory pathways (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversible inhibition of acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Reversible inhibition of acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits iodination and coupling","bool":true},{"option":"Promotes iodination and coupling","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of the following is the long-acting analog of somatostatin?","answers":[{"option":"Glargine","bool":false},{"option":"Octreotide","bool":true},{"option":"Levothyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Propylthiouracil","bool":false},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which drug inhibits growth hormone?","answers":[{"option":"Nutropin","bool":false},{"option":"Octreotide","bool":true},{"option":"Genotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Norditropin","bool":false},{"option":"Serostim","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A patient presents with having a mass in the pituitary fossa, hyperglycemia, and renal calculi. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudohypoparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2B (MEN 2B)","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple endocrine neoplasia type 1 (MEN1)","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple endocrine neoplasia type 2A (MEN 2A)","bool":false},{"option":"Von Hippel-Lindau (VHL) syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of the following medications are best to treat a case of prolactinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Beta adrenergic agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Antihistamines","bool":false},{"option":"Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine agonists","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Excessive growth hormone release in adults leads to which condition?","answers":[{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Gigantism","bool":false},{"option":"Goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Acromegaly","bool":true},{"option":"Dwarfism","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A defect of the diencephalon causes reduction of which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibin","bool":false},{"option":"Somatostatin","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":true},{"option":"Growth hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of these is false regarding the pituitary gland?","answers":[{"option":"Oxytocin and antidiuretic hormone are released by the posterior pituitary","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior pituitary is called neurohypophysis","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior pituitary is also called the adenohypophysis","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenocorticotrophic hormone is released by anterior pituitary","bool":false},{"option":"It lies in fossa of the zygomatic bone","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What are somatotrophs?","answers":[{"option":"Growth homrone producing basophilic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Throxine releasing cells","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone producing acidophilic cells","bool":true},{"option":"Somatostatin producing basophilic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Somatostatin producing acidophilic cells","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 13-year-old boy is brought to the emergency department in an unconscious state. On examination, dehydration signs and fruity breath is observed. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hypovolemic shock","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Neovascularization around the optic nerve head is due to which reason?","answers":[{"option":"Pre-proliferative diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Gluacoma","bool":false},{"option":"Proliferative diabetic retinopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Retinal vein occlusion","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the marked macrovascular complication of type 2 diabetes mellitus?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal vein occlusion","bool":false},{"option":"Accelerated arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Accelerated atherosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Diminishing vision","bool":false},{"option":"Tunnel vision","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of the following is appropriate regarding the thyroid?","answers":[{"option":"It is an exocrine gland","bool":false},{"option":"Only right recurrent laryngeal nerve passes through the thyroid","bool":false},{"option":"It has four lobes","bool":false},{"option":"It produces thyroxine only","bool":false},{"option":"Sometimes supplied by the thyroid ima artery","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of the following is an adverse effect of thyroxine?","answers":[{"option":"Weight gain","bool":false},{"option":"Easy bruising","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Hirsutism","bool":false},{"option":"Angina","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 35-year-old man comes to the outpatient department with complaints of chest pain, shortness of breath, nausea, and pain in the right upper abdomen. He is a known case of hypothyroidism. He has raised jugular venous pressure, fast breathing, and increased heart rate. What is the most probable diagnosis for his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Appendicitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardial effusion","bool":true},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Gallstones","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 20-year-old nurse comes to the outpatient department with complaints of hyperactivity, mood swings, difficulty sleeping, diarrhea, and increased sensitivity to heat. She also complains of muscle weakness and feels tired all the time. The doctor orders a 24-hour I-131 uptake test and it shows an iodine uptake of 1.7%, which is below the normal range of 7.5% to 25%. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Dequervain thyroiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Graves’ disease","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic multinodular goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Factitious thyrotoxicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Toxic adenoma","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the most sensitive test for the diagnosis of primary hypothyroidism?","answers":[{"option":"Thyroglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Total T3 level","bool":false},{"option":"Free T4 level","bool":false},{"option":"TSH level","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroid antibodies","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Hürthle cell variant is seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Papillary carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Anaplastic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Marginal zone lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the most common thyroid carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Follicular carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Papillary cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Anaplastic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hürthle cell tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 45-year-old female presented with a nodule in her thyroid region. What is the most common thyroid carcinoma in this age group?","answers":[{"option":"Papillary carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Medullary cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hürthle cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Anaplastic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which thyroid carcinoma is associated with increased calcitonin levels?","answers":[{"option":"Medullary cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Follicular carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hürthle cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Anaplastic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Papillary carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 7-year-old kid presents to the outpatient department with a protruding tongue, mental retardation, umbilical hernia, and coarse facial features. He is diagnosed with cretinism. A deficiency of which hormone can cause this?","answers":[{"option":"Somatostatin","bool":false},{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which does not cause diabetes mellitus?","answers":[{"option":"Cushing syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Glucagonoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acromegaly","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 24-year-old woman comes into the outpatient department with complaints of weight gain, muscle weakness,  thin arms and legs, increased fat around the base of the neck, and easy bruising in the last six months. She has also developed abdominal striae. What is the cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"No adrenal masses","bool":false},{"option":"An adrenal mass of > 2 cm","bool":true},{"option":"Enlargement of thyroid gland","bool":false},{"option":"No nodules","bool":false},{"option":"A hot nodule in thyroid","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the effect of the dexamethasone suppression test on ectopic adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Only sensitive to high doses","bool":false},{"option":"Only sensitive to low doses","bool":false},{"option":"Sensitive to both high and low doses","bool":false},{"option":"Insensitive to low or high doses","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"What is the most common source of ectopic adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) production?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell lung carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial carcinoid","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a clinical feature of Cushing syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Bruising","bool":false},{"option":"Orthostatic hypotension","bool":true},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose intolerance","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A 57-year-old woman comes to the clinic with complaints of tingling sensation in her fingertips, toes, and lips, accompanied by twitching of facial muscles. She also has muscle pains or cramps, particularly in her legs and feet. She also complains of mood changes and tiredness. Her skin has become increasingly dry and rough in the last five months. Laboratory tests reveal a low blood calcium level, low parathyroid hormone level, high blood phosphorus level, and a low blood magnesium level. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Familial hypocalciuric hypercalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoparathyroidism","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudopseudohypoparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudohypoparathyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/endocrinology/2019","question":"A patient presents with the complaint that he gets dizzy and experiences blurred vision and fatigue within three minutes of standing up from a supine position. He is confirmed to have orthostatic hypotension. Physical examination reveals hyperpigmentation of palmar creases, nipples, and axillary region. What is the most likely cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Addison disease","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Vitmain D deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false}]}]
export default arr